Why is Lancer helping them?
What is it, Caster?
Is there a problem?
No, it is a trivial matter.
Please do not trouble yourself.
There is nothing to be concerned about.
I see.
Master...
There is something that I would like to ask you.
What is it?
Earlier, in this chapel, you said something.
That you would be unable to achieve your own objective.
But to my knowledge, you have no desire of your own.
People desire to obtain something, to destroy something,
to forgive something...
and yet you have never spoken of any
of these desires that all humans possess.
Even so, you still have an objective?
Perhaps.
I was treated as something not human.
I grew up never doubting that to be true.
As a result, I eventually took a life.
I bore that person no ill will,
and it was not that I stood to profit from killing him.
It was mechanical—carried out as per another's orders.
At that moment, I decided for myself that I was not human.
Though it would be easy to blame
the environment in which I was raised,
my choices were mine alone.
As you said, I have no wish to change myself.
I have always believed myself to be solely responsible for the way I live.
However...
There is something I must return to its rightful place.
Having a goal beyond simple existence seems strange after all this time.
It is a laughably self-indulgent thing.
But in the end, that is what all wishes are.
We need to defeat Caster before the fight between Lancer and Archer ends.
The Dark Sword Bares Its Fangs
I know.
You're sure I can leave Caster to you, Tohsaka?
Yes.
She'll probably push me to the brink, but stay out of it, okay?
You just keep Kuzuki-sensei as far away as you can.
Understood.
Berserker is gone.
The biggest problem we have left is Blondie.
But if we can get Archer and Saber
back from Caster, we can beat him.
And then the Holy Grail War will be over.
Looks like she wants to wrap this up too.
To think I graciously spared your life.
Have you come to throw it away, little girl?
I didn't come to throw anything away.
I came take back what's mine.
Plus, I really can't stand you,
so bringing you down will be a bonus.
Saber...
I offer my compliments on winning Lancer over to your side.
But you still lack the necessary pieces to win.
Are you such a naïve child that you cannot manage such a simple analysis?
I've been thinking this for a while now.
That outfit of yours is a bit, you know...
A purple robe, in this day and age?
What kind of bumpkin wears that?
Also, this is your idea of a magic workshop?
You're so stuck in the past it's laughable.
Oh, dear.
Are all mages of this era so foolhardy?
Now I understand why Archer deserted you.
Kuzuki can see everything.
That we're trying to split them up,
and that you have a trick up your sleeve.
And even with that knowledge,
he's letting Caster do things her way.
Shall we get started, then?
This will be my third time facing you.
And I'm getting awfully sick of your ugly mug,
so this time, I'll finish you off for good.
Bold words.
Do you honestly think you can defeat me, little girl?
Of course I can beat your parlor tricks.
Was there ever any doubt?
A first-rate mage like myself could never lose to a third-rate hack like you!
I can see by your insolence that you are in need of harsh discipline.
Trace on!
He knows exactly what our plan is.
I won't be able to buy time for long.
Caster and her Master, a close-quarters specialist who had even Saber on the ropes...
Martial arts and magic.
By all rights, we should have no chance of winning
when we're outclassed in both.
Meaning that the purpose of this battle is to
hold out long enough to set Tohsaka's plan in motion.
Can we do it, considering how hopelessly outmatched we are?
Bit different to that other night, don't you think?
Sorry I had to go easy on you last time.
My Master imposed a ridiculous Command Spell that ordered me
to return alive without killing any opponents.
But I'm not bound by that order now.
This time, I won't hold back...
and I'll kill you.
I can't figure you out.
You're this skilled, but you chose to side with Caster?
If you'd stuck with the little lady,
you probably would've been a match for her.
I hear you out, and you're still going on about that?
I chose the option with the higher chance of success, however slight.
Is that so?
It was stupid of me to even ask.
No argument there.
But there's no honor in that.
You have a fatal lack of pride in your sword skills.
Yes.
Unfortunately, I am devoid of pride.
But why does that bother you?
Does it tarnish the title of "hero"?
Don't make me laugh, Lancer.
Dishonor can be washed away with success.
Feed your unnecessary pride to the dogs.
Dogs, you say?
I mean it, Cú Chulainn.
If you have a hero's pride, cast it aside while you still can.
Well said.
Then you first.
You've heard of my spear's special ability, haven't you, Archer?
Of course.
It has a cunning curse that reverses cause and effect.
It's certainly fearsome, but unless you get close,
it's nothing but a sharp stinger.
True.
But spears can also be used like this.
Here it comes.
May this strike be your requiem.
I'm well aware...
Gae Bolg, the spear whose curse kills with a single blow.
I know that when thrown,
it is an anti-army Noble Phantasm.
It pierces the heart, hitting its mark every time.
In which case, taking the blow head-on is the only option.
Gae Bolg!
I am the bone of my sword.
Rho Aias!
Son of a...
Not even Aias,
which deflected the javelin of Troy's greatest hero
during the Trojan War, can take this?
I'm surprised.
To think there is a spear that can penetrate Rho Aias...
The weapon you hold is mightier than even the original Gungnir.
Who the hell are you?
Just a simple bowman.
Nonsense.
As if bowmen carry shields that can withstand a Noble Phantasm.
Under the right circumstances, they might.
But you can see that it didn't entirely work.
Even though I expended most of my mana,
one of my arms was rendered useless,
and my Aias was completely destroyed.
Damn it... That was the most powerful defense I had.
But enough about that, Lancer. Have you noticed?
Caster must be hard pressed.
Her prying eyes have stopped watching.
Have they now?
I thought that might be what you were up to,
you sly bastard.
That was your intent all along?
Of course.
I told you, didn't I?
I only use the means that give me the highest chance of victory.
You sink lower each time, you bastard.
But my job here is done.
Sieben!
Seven!
What was that tremor a minute ago?
His goal is to take away these two blades.
Rushed projections and impromptu swords won't be as effective.
I can make two more at most.
My job is to keep Kuzuki occupied.
I'm not going to quit before that job is finished.
Acht!
Eight!
You struggle so valiantly.
I did not think that you had such a trick up your sleeve,
little girl.
Sieben!
Seven!
You are fending off my attacks completely.
Valiant indeed.
You wouldn't need to use as many gems if you only protected yourself.
Yes, I know that I'm using them wastefully.
Caster's spells cover too broad an area.
Kuzuki is probably protected,
but if I don't nullify her spells, Shirou will be burned to death.
You still intend to defend the both of you?
Your determination is impressive, but how long can you hold out?
If all you do is block me, the outcome is obvious, little girl.
Six gems left...
Sechs! Ein Fluß, ein Halt!
Six! A river, a stop!
Fünf, Drei, Vier.
Five, three, four.
Der Riese und brennt das ein Ende!
The giant and burns that an end!
Oh, have you finished?
You have more gems, do you not?
Why not keep trying until you run out?
Those were my biggest attacks.
Since those failed,
even if I were to combine a hundred gems,
my magic wouldn't be powerful enough.
Oh, I see that you finally understand.
No matter what you try, you are no match for me.
But it was quite entertaining.
It has been quite some time since I last fought a magic duel.
Yes, I consider you worthwhile, if only for that.
Does that frustrate you? It is nevertheless the truth.
You should actually be proud.
You forced me into a magic duel.
It is only a matter of time before that boy is beaten by my Master.
Let us finish this before then, shall we?
Stark, groß, Zwei!
Strong, big, two!
You profess to be a mage, and yet you fight with your fists?
Sorry, but for mages nowadays, the art of self-defense
is a required subject!
That's enough.
No way...
Tohsaka!
You missed your chance.
Failing to kill her after four strikes betrays your lack of ability.
You have my thanks, Master.
Had you not intervened, I would have been defeated.
Spare me the flattery.
What you need to do now is wake up Saber.
Clearly, these are not opponents to be underestimated.
Yes.
That is a wise decision, Master.
Indeed.
If only it had come a few seconds earlier.
Trace...
on.
Souichirou!
Are you unharmed, Master?
Yes.
I am glad.
It would not do...
if you were to die.
It is a pity, though.
I had finally found my wish.
There is no need to grieve.
I will fulfill your wish in your place.
That is impossible.
After all, until this moment...
my wish...
had already been granted.
Archer...
I'd always suspected this,
but is it true?
"Trace on."
That's definitely what he said.
He spoke exactly the same words that I do.
We had a snake in our midst, eh?
This was your goal all along, wasn't it, Archer?
Yes.
But if I had to pick a metaphor,
the Trojan Horse would be more apt.
Since it was a hero of Greek myth who was just defeated.
I see.
Letting a man like you into her ranks was Caster's undoing.
If you want to continue this battle, I won't stop you.
Wait...
Why are you still going, Kuzuki?
Caster's gone.
You shouldn't have any reason to fight!
You're right. I have no reason to fight.
Like you, I never had any interest in the Holy Grail.
Then why?
This is something that I started.
I took up this charge, without caring about matters of good or evil.
I can't quit without seeing it through.
Saber...
Shirou?
Wha—
Damn, I missed.
Archer! What do you think you're doing?
You can drop the act!
Caster's been beaten,
so I won't stand for any more of your nonsense!
You won't stand for it?
Why do I need your permission?
You aren't my Master.
My contract with you was severed.
I don't believe it.
Why are you doing this, Archer?
You still want to kill Shirou?
Yes.
I will kill Emiya Shirou with my own two hands.
That is the only desire I, a man reduced to a Guardian,
have left.
Die here, along with your false mentor.
Archer, your wish is wrong.
You want to give me a piece of your mind? Fine, let's hear it.
Then I entrust my fate to your sword!
A Destiny Forged in the Beginning
Next Time